In 1925,
a town in Alaska
is running out of
time.
Kids are getting sick,
and the medicine is
nearly 700 miles away.
Ships can't get through
the ice,
planes can't fly in
that cold.
So they send dogs.
Twenty sled teams will
pass it along,
like a relay.
One team gets the
hardest part.
Its leader is a
12 -year -old dog
called Togo.
They run 170 miles
just to reach it,
then turn around and
race back.
Togo takes a shortcut
across a frozen sea
in a blizzard.
That night the storm
blows all that ice
out to sea.
They crossed it just
in time.
261 miles,
more than any other
team.
Five and a half
days later,
the medicine arrives and
the outbreak is stopped.
But the dog who
ran the last 53
miles gets the statue
in New York.
His name was Balto.
Togo had to wait
76 years for his.
Follow ViralRobloxGames for
more stories like this.